<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>baloo on Vishesh Handa's blog</title><link>http://vhanda.in/tags/baloo/</link><description>Recent content in baloo on Vishesh Handa's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 16:57:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vhanda.in/tags/baloo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Baloo 5.15</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2015/10/Baloo-5.15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 16:57:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2015/10/Baloo-5.15/</guid><description>We have a new release of Baloo. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know about it - It&amp;rsquo;s a file indexing and searching solution for Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s quite fast, and shipped by default in KDE Plasma.
Baloo is part of KDE Frameworks and has a fast 1 month release cycle. So, I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to be spamming you about the big changes in Baloo each month.
The 5.15 release focused a lot on tooling and bug fixing.</description></item><item><title>Baloo and NodeJs</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2015/08/Baloo-and-NodeJs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 19:01:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2015/08/Baloo-and-NodeJs/</guid><description>I took some time to write some very basic nodejs bindings for Baloo. They are available on github and npm.
Example It can be installed via npm install baloo
var Baloo = require(&amp;#39;baloo&amp;#39;); var query = new Baloo.Query(&amp;#39;keyword&amp;#39;); query.exec(function(results) { results.forEach(function(filePath) { console.log(filePath); }); }); I&amp;rsquo;m aware of a few people who have deployed Baloo on a server. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this will help them. It also paves the way for some interesting web-based user interfaces for file-searching.</description></item><item><title>KDE and The Semantic Desktop</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2015/03/KDE-and-The-Semantic-Desktop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 17:11:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2015/03/KDE-and-The-Semantic-Desktop/</guid><description>During the KDE4 years the Semantic Desktop was one of the main pillars of KDE. Nepomuk was a massive, all encompassing, and integrated with many different part of KDE. However few people know what The Semantic Desktop was all about, and where KDE is heading.
History The Semantic Desktop as it was originally envisioned comprised of both the technology and the philosophy behind The Semantic Web.
The Semantic Web is built on top of RDF and Graphs.</description></item><item><title>Desktop Search Configuration</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2014/04/Desktop-Search-Configuration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 17:09:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2014/04/Desktop-Search-Configuration/</guid><description>Update: This blog post is quite old and does not reflect the current state of Desktop Search in KDE. If you&amp;rsquo;re just looking to disable it, you can either run the $ balooctl disable command or go to System Settings -&amp;gt; Search -&amp;gt; File Search -&amp;gt; Disable.
KDE SC 4.13 is finally out. As you may have heard this marks the release of Baloo. The bear is now out in the wild!</description></item></channel></rss>