<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>emacs on Vishesh Handa's blog</title><link>http://vhanda.in/tags/emacs/</link><description>Recent content in emacs on Vishesh Handa's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 19:58:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vhanda.in/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Emacs : A summary</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/02/Emacs-A-summary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 19:58:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/02/Emacs-A-summary/</guid><description>I know I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting a lot of Emacs centric posts lately, but this is the last one. For now. I had always found Emacs to be this invigorating, powerful hacker tool, which one mastered would make me a billion times more efficient. And despite everything, I still think that way, but its just not for me.
My Emacs journey was rocky. That&amp;rsquo;s the best way to describe it. Initially I was irritated by the key bindings, then I gradually came to accept them, then I started to love them, and now I hate other applications for not having them.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Emacs</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/01/Configuring-Emacs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 04:05:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/01/Configuring-Emacs/</guid><description>I finally started to configure Emacs, specifically for C++ and Python. And let me tell you one thing - Emacs is NOT made for newbies or people who have used graphical user interfaces their entire lives. It will be a huge, and I mean huge, learning curve. Will it be worth it? Hell, I&amp;rsquo;m still waiting to find out. And, here is another thing - If you do not know how to type properly.</description></item><item><title>Emacs Hype</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2009/12/Emacs-Hype/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 13:32:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2009/12/Emacs-Hype/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never really understood the hype behind Emacs (and Vi), but thats probably because I&amp;rsquo;ve never had the patience to actually use them. I always plan to learn how to, and I do. I read the introduction part, familiarize myself with the keys, but thats all that ever happens. Yesterday, I planned to start using it again, because I read an article saying &amp;ldquo;How AWESOME it is&amp;rdquo;, I even started reading The Emacs Lisp Manual.</description></item></channel></rss>