<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kde on Vishesh Handa's blog</title><link>http://vhanda.in/tags/kde/</link><description>Recent content in kde on Vishesh Handa's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 22:22:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://vhanda.in/tags/kde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nepomuk Tag Manager</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2012/01/Nepomuk-Tag-Manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 22:22:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2012/01/Nepomuk-Tag-Manager/</guid><description>Welcome to Nepomuk Tag Week! Well, not really, since it&amp;rsquo;s not an official thing. I&amp;rsquo;ve just been working a lot with tags lately, and this week I&amp;rsquo;m going to be spamming you with some tag related updates (One for every day of the week, minus Monday)
I thought I&amp;rsquo;ll start with something small - Tag Management.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been badly needing a UI to allow the users to modify, merge and delete their tags.</description></item><item><title>Shaastra</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/09/Shaastra/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 12:04:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/09/Shaastra/</guid><description>In India, we have 16 premier engineering institutes. They go by the name of IIT (Indian Institute of Technology), and are considered one of top engineering colleges in India.
In a couple of hours, I&amp;rsquo;ll be flying down to IIT Madras to attend their annual technical festival: Shaastra. I&amp;rsquo;ve been invited to conduct a hackfest, whose primary objective would be to introduce people to the world of KDE. From what I know, there are 25 people signed up right now.</description></item><item><title>Notably v0.3</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/09/Notably-v0.3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2011 12:58:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/09/Notably-v0.3/</guid><description>I finally decided on a name - Nepomuk Notes is now known as notably.
Unlike last time, Notably now has its own project page on projects.kde.org.
This release adds a sidebar which lets you browse your notes, sorted in a reverse chronological order.
Next Steps Make/Find someone to create a nice icon Allow browsing by tags Better KWin integration</description></item><item><title>Nepomuk Notes v0.2</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/09/Nepomuk-Notes-v0.2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 16:58:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/09/Nepomuk-Notes-v0.2/</guid><description>Another week has gone by and I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to release another version of my favorite note taking application. Like last time the code is still in my scratch repository.
New Features Tagging Support I&amp;rsquo;ve added tagging support. So, now you can tag all your notes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use the traditional tagging widget, and wanted something that was more usable. So I ended up with a simple text box where you can type your tags.</description></item><item><title>Nepomuk Audio Search</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/03/Nepomuk-Audio-Search/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 07:33:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/03/Nepomuk-Audio-Search/</guid><description>This is something I showcased at my talk in conf.kde.in. I coded it in a couple of hours. It is a lot of fun to play around with! I can’t wait to index all my videos this way.
youtube d41bmTSogA4
Impressive? :D
This was showcased at the beginning of the Nepomuk talk under the section “Nepomuk is not about searching, but here are some cool things that it can do!”</description></item><item><title>conf.kde.in is going to rock!</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/02/conf.kde.in-is-going-to-rock/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 11:14:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2011/02/conf.kde.in-is-going-to-rock/</guid><description>I’m going to state the most utterly insane thing I can think of – “You have not heard about conf.kde.in!“. I know, I’m crazy! But just in case you haven’t – conf.kde.in is the first Indian KDE Conference to be held in Bengalurufrom the 9th – 13th March.
We have a spectacular list of talksabout topics ranging from Localization to Packaging to hard core coding! Additionally we have a series of workshops planned to get you started with KDE, and, help, you discover the amazing KDE community.</description></item><item><title>Nepomuk Backup</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/11/Nepomuk-Backup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2010 07:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/11/Nepomuk-Backup/</guid><description>Roughly 2 weeks ago, just before the feature freeze, the Nepomuk backupsync service was pushed into the trunk.
A long time ago I posted a lot of features about the ‘planned’ Nepomuk Backup service. I did land up implementing most of those features, but ultimately disabled some of them for a more stable backup experience. I thought it would be better to have a stable backup tool, without all the frills, compared to unstable tool which may potentially mess up your data.</description></item><item><title>Nepomuk: Backup &amp; Sync</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/06/Nepomuk-Backup-Sync/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2010 00:02:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/06/Nepomuk-Backup-Sync/</guid><description>﻿How time flies.. a month of the official coding period is already over, and I&amp;rsquo;m nowhere even close to saying that this part works perfectly. Most of my code is still in the requires exhaustive testing stages, but I can say that the core parts have been implemented.
In case you&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten, or didn&amp;rsquo;t read the title, I&amp;rsquo;m implementing Metadata Backup &amp;amp; Sync. Well I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be implementing sharing as well, but ignore that for now.</description></item><item><title>Nepomuk GSoCer's Project Introduction</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/04/Nepomuk-GSoCers-Project-Introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 21:43:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/04/Nepomuk-GSoCers-Project-Introduction/</guid><description>Is GSoCer even a word? It seems like a Gnome version of soccer :-/
Well, this is my first post to the Planet, and I suppose an Introduction is warranted.
My name is Vishesh Handa, and I&amp;rsquo;m currently in my second year of B.Tech in Computer Science at Galgotia&amp;rsquo;s College of Engineering, India. I&amp;rsquo;ll be officially working on Nepomuk during the summer. (Yaye!) My project is labeled Metadata backup, sync and sharing.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2010</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/04/Google-Summer-of-Code-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 23:24:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/04/Google-Summer-of-Code-2010/</guid><description>I GOT IN!!
Link!Hurray!!</description></item><item><title>Got a KDE SVN account</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/04/Got-a-KDE-SVN-account/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2010 17:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/04/Got-a-KDE-SVN-account/</guid><description>Before I say anything else, scream with me - &amp;ldquo;Wooo Hooo&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Yippee&amp;rdquo;. You didn&amp;rsquo;t scream, did you? :-(
Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m officially allowed to commit my changes now! Yaye!
:-D</description></item><item><title>First KDE Contribution</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/03/First-KDE-Contribution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2010 11:50:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/03/First-KDE-Contribution/</guid><description>Okay! So, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been posting at all. I know, I know! :-(
BUT, I made my first actual contribution to KDE a couple of days back! Hurray! :-D The last time I tried to fix a bug, it never really got accepted or rejected. The developer of KSnapshot never returned my emails, even after I pointed out that it was my first patch. This really dissuaded by from contributing to KSnapshot, and even though I knew how to fix other bugs, I never actually got down to doing it.</description></item><item><title>Fixing a bug :KDE</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/02/Fixing-a-bug-KDE/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2010 00:28:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/02/Fixing-a-bug-KDE/</guid><description>EDIT: I&amp;rsquo;d just like to say that I did NOT solve the bug, and I introduced another one in the process. But it was a good learning experience. :)
A couple of weeks back I started learning about Qt, and then about KDE. I thought it was time I start contributing, specially since I can. KDE consists of million lines of code, and getting acquainted with such a huge system is a terribly daunting task.</description></item><item><title>What I love about Qt</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/02/What-I-love-about-Qt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 18:53:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/02/What-I-love-about-Qt/</guid><description>For the past week I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning about the Qt Framework, mainly cause I want to start contributing to KDE, instead of just bitching about what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, or how awesome it is! :-P
In case you&amp;rsquo;re unaware, Qt is an application framework for developing cross-platform GUI applications. TrollTech started it in 1991, and Nokia bought it in June 2008. Qt applications can even be ported to Nokia&amp;rsquo;s Symbian platform for mobiles.</description></item><item><title>Desktops in general</title><link>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/01/Desktops-in-general/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2010 00:37:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vhanda.in/blog/2010/01/Desktops-in-general/</guid><description>Anyone reading this post should be warned that I&amp;rsquo;m really sleepy right now. I have this sudden urge to type about this not so random topic. I am sleepy and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take this post to seriously. I&amp;rsquo;m just ranting ..
Has anyone ever realized that our Desktops in general are really static. There is nothing about it that changes that often. Okay, maybe the wallpaper. But how often does that happen?</description></item></channel></rss>